hindustantimes.com 2001-12-18

# Hindustantimes.com - Policy

**_

#### Privacy Statement

_**

Users of this web site, being the hindustantimes.com web site or any other web site amongst its network of web sites (collectively the "hindustantimes Websites") should read the contents hereof forming the Privacy Statement through which the hindustantimes Websites are attempting to define the privacy parameters and use of certain personal information collected from its users online, while such users are accessing and making use of, the various Services available to them on the hindustantimes Websites, such information being your name, home or business address, gender, year of birth, occupation, telephone or fax phone numbers and e-mail address which you agree, in consideration for access to and use of the Services provided on the hindustantimes Websites, to provide as current, complete, and accurate registration information (the "Registration Data") as prompted to do by the Site, and to maintain and update this Registration Data as required to keep it current, complete and accurate. All Registration Data will be utilised by hindustantimes Websites or any of them only in accordance with the discretion exercised by you, the user, at the time of providing the Registration Data. 

Please be advised that your access and use, of each hindustantimes Website is subject to this Privacy Statement, unless specific Privacy Statements are contained within each hindustantimes Website. If any of the statements, terms, conditions and notices contained in this Privacy Statement conflict with those stated or contained within any other particular hindustantimes Website, then the Privacy Statement contained on such hindustantimes Website shall control the access and use of that specific hindustantimes Website. 

All capitalised terms used in this Privacy Statement and not specifically defined have the same meaning as given to them in the hindustantimes Websites General Terms of Use. You can go to Terms to cross reference the General Terms of Use that apply to the hindustantimes Websites. 

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to make Modifications to this Privacy Statement, at any time, and will make sincere efforts to inform you of such Modifications. Please help us by checking this Privacy Statement periodically for such Modifications. Your continued access to the hindustantimes Websites following the posting of Modifications will mean you accept those Modifications. 

By your accessing the hindustantimes Websites you agree to respect the privacy of other users on the hindustantimes Websites and maintain the same information given to or accessed by you or in any other manner available to you, as private and confidential unless otherwise agreed. 

#### 1\. Registration Data 

The Registration Data and such other Personal Information as defined hereinbelow that you may provide us, at your discretion, helps us to create the hindustantimes Websites experience, one which is reasonably suited to your requirements. Furthermore, once you have registered with the hindustantimes Websites you will be provided a hindustantimes ID to enable you to avail of such Services that you may choose. Personal Information for the purpose of this Privacy Statement shall mean such information as shall be provided by you at your discretion, when required or asked for by the hindustantimes Websites other than the Registration Data. In general, addresses (the Internet address of a computer) are logged to track a user's session while the user remains anonymous. We analyse this data for certain trends and statistics, such as which parts of our hindustantimes Websites users are visiting and how long they spend there. In general, we do not link your IP addresses to anything personally identifiable to you. 

#### 2\. Cookies

One of the other ways that hindustantimes Websites may collect personal information is through the use of cookies which we use for several things such as for estimating the number of users that a particular area within the hindustantimes Website attracts, to access your Registration Data once we get to know of your identity and your area of visit or in the case of any shopping sites, to assist the vendors on the website to better understand their audience, their shopping patterns and the kind of pages visited by the users to such vendors' webstore. Some of the other usage's of cookies are to track your status in any event such as a contest hosted by the hindustantimes Websites or by any of their partners or sponsors.

For your better understanding let us explain what a cookie is. A cookie is a small data file that certain web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie is a commonly used tool, and is generally used across the industry to provide useful features for their customers. A cookie file can contain information such as user ID that the particular hindustantimes Website uses to track the pages you have visited. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie cannot read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. As part of our efforts to offer and provide customized and personalized services, hindustantimes Websites use cookies to store and sometimes track information about you. Almost all sites on hindustantimes Websites where you are prompted to log-in or that are customized require that you accept cookies. 

You may exercise your discretion as regards cookies at any time by modifying your browser preferences. By so doing you have the choice of accepting or rejecting cookies (rejection of all cookies will disable you to use those hindustantimes Websites' Services where registration is required for participation), or of being notified when one is set.

Third party sponsors, alliance partners of hindustantimes Websites or advertisers may have cookies developed and controlled by them on the hindustantimes Websites. We do not have access to these cookies or any information that they may contain. 

#### 3\. Our Alliance/Business Partners and Sponsors 

You do understand and appreciate that in order to provide the Services, many of which are free the support of our sponsors and advertisers is indeed critical and invaluable to the hindustantimes Websites We try and put our efforts in providing only such advertisements and content as may be of potential use and particular interest to you. We may conduct this targeting of specific audiences through banner advertisements and/or e-mail, based on the profiles and parameters in respect of the target audience as may be desired by the advertiser. We make our best efforts to disallow the advertisers direct access to your individual account information. hindustantimes Websites may undertake research on your personal profile, areas of interests, and behaviour based on the Registration Data and Personal Information provided by you, and analyse the research on an aggregated basis, which the hindustantimes Websites may share with their advertisers and/ or alliance/business partners.

By accessing the hindustantimes Websites or any of them, you agree and grant the hindustantimes Websites the right to disclose the aggregate Registration Data and Personal Information to third parties in connection with marketing the hindustantimes Websites and Services and that the hindustantimes Websites may themselves choose to use your individual Registration Data and Personal Information to provide targeting of advertisements and other offers of the Services through banner advertisements, e-mails or otherwise. 

#### 4\. Disclosure by the hindustantimes Websites

The hindustantimes Websites will not, in the normal course, disclose your Registration Data or Personal Information, save and except 

(i) with your permission, as exercised by your discretion; or

(ii) when required under law to do so; or 

(iii) when such disclosure is in our opinion, necessary to maintain the operations and servicing of the hindustantimes Websites and systems or improve our Services. 

(iv) when such disclosure is in our opinion necessary, to protect and defend the rights and property of the hindustantimes Websites; or

(v) when such disclosure is in our opinion necessary, to act in an emergency to protect the personal safety of our users or the public. 

(vi) when such disclosure is in our opinion necessary, to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating the General Terms of Use of the hindustantimes Websites. 

#### 5\. Optional Use of Information 

Some of the other ways in which we may use your information, if necessary, is for enabling transactions to take place on the hindustantimes Websites that you choose to avail of in a manner due and commercially viable to both yourself and the vendor/merchant whose store/website you may visit and where any third party interaction is required, such as your credit card number and contact information. Please be advised that the hindustantimes Websites have no responsibility or take no liability for the policies regarding privacy and data collection that the vendors/merchants or third parties may have, which are independent of this Privacy Statement. 

Further, we may share your Personal Information with our various alliance/business partners or sponsors. Certain data collected during a hindustantimes Website promotion may be shared with a alliance/business partners or sponsors, in accordance with the discretion exercised by you at the time of registration or when you chose to participate in such promotion. You should be aware that at any time where you are given the opportunity to seek information from alliance/business partners or sponsors, you by the act of so requesting, for such information from our alliance/business partners or sponsors give the hindustantimes Websites permission to transfer your personal information to such alliance/business partners or sponsor so they can service you accordingly. If you do not wish to allow your data to be shared with our various alliance/business partners, sponsors, or third parties that you may interact with, you can choose not to use a particular service or not to participate in certain promotions or contests. 

As stated earlier and as agreed and granted by you the hindustantimes Webster may disclose aggregated user statistics to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes. 

#### 6\. Links

Please be advised that this Privacy Statement does not cover the information practices of those web sites linked to hindustantimes Websites.

hindustantimes Websites are not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of web sites to which its sites are linked in any manner or means. Such links to third party web sites on hindustantimes Websites are provided solely as a convenience to you And these may collect personally identifiable information about you hindustantimes Websites has not reviewed all of such third party sites and does not endorse or make any representations or commitments about or on them, or on any information, software or other products or materials or advertisements found there, or any results/benefits that may be obtained from using them. If you decide to access any of the third party sites linked to hindustantimes Websites, you do so entirely on your own responsibility. This Privacy Statement does not cover the information practices of those web sites linked to hindustantimes Websites. Further, hindustantimes Websites do not control the availability of such third party web sites. Any concerns regarding any such service or resource or third party web site, or any link thereto, should be directed to the particular service or resource. 

#### 7\. Health and Financial Information

It is important to us to keep private any personal financial and health-related information connected with users. Knowing that you use certain services or features may help us to offer you better and more relevant content and advertisements. But we do not make this available to any third parties without your permission. Any user statistics that we may provide to prospective advertisers or partners regarding financial products or health related service usage on hindustantimes Websites are provided in the aggregate only and do not include any personally identifiable information about any individual user. 

Please note that secure socket encryption is utilised for the transmission of credit card numbers when asked for in respect of a transaction. 

**

8\. Security

**

Please remember that protection of your privacy begins with you and you have the sole responsibility therefor. At the bare minimum, in order to avoid others from accessing your personal information and correspondence, you should adhere to the following:

a) do not reveal your password to anyone; 

b) sign out of your hindustantimes Websites account when you are done; 

c) close your browser window when you are done. 

Please read the General Terms of Use pertaining to your undertakings with regard to use of the Services on or through the hindustantimes Websites.

Further, please keep in mind that information that has been voluntarily disclosed on a forum that is accessible to public can be accessed and utilised by others and on account of such access you may receive unsolicited messages from such parties who access such information. Also, please be advised that you should not reveal your password if you should receive any unsolicited email or phone call requiring you to so reveal your password as it is not the practice of hindustantimes Websites to require users to reveal their passwords in such an unsolicited manner. 

Whenever hindustantimes Websites handle personal information as described above hindustantimes Websites use their best efforts, to ensure that such personal information is handled in accordance with the relevant General Terms of Use and this Privacy Statement. 

You understand and acknowledge that transmission of data over the Internet cannot always be completely secure. hindustantimes Websites use their best efforts to protect your personal information but cannot and do not warrant the security of any information, and you must do so at your own risk. The hindustantimes Websites assume no liability for disclosure of data due to, errors in transmission or unauthorised third parties. 

We remind you that this Privacy Statement is subject to Modifications at any time and we will make sincere efforts to inform you of such Modifications. Please help us by checking this Privacy Statement periodically for such Modifications. Your continued access to the hindustantimes Websites following the posting of Modifications will mean you accept those Modifications.
